자막출처: 메가무비
http://sig.kornet.net/gomovie/
"그녀의 이름은 레드 소냐
폭력이 난무하던 머나먼 옛날의 미개한 시대에
용맹한 빨간 머리의 여전사
하이보리안 왕국에서는 정의와 복수를 위한
소냐의 모험이 전설로 내려오고 있다
그 전설은 이렇게 시작된다"
Sonja.
소냐
소냐!
You are suffering, Sonja...
고난의 세월이었다..소냐!
그러나 복수는 네 몫이다
but vengeance shall be yours.
네가 원하는
Vengeance on Queen Gedren...
who wanted you for herself.
게드린 여왕에 대한 복수...
Your disgust was clear.
복수에 불 타 있겠지
그것은 네 가족을 게드린이 살해했기 때문이겠지
And so it was that Gedren
ordered your family murdered...
your body violated by her soldiers.
네 몸은 그들 병사에게 유린당하고
그러나 너의 정의감과 복수심의
요청으로...
But in your quest
for justice and vengeance...
you will need great strength...
강한 힘을 필요로 할거야..
칼을 들기에는 힘이 약하니
for your sword arm must have no equal.
I give you that strength.
나는 너에게 그 힘을 주겠노라
레드 소냐
Varna, where is the Lord of Hyrkania?
바나, 하이카니아 군주는 어딨지?
He has not come, Highness.
오지 않았습니다, 사제님
He should be here
for the destruction of the talisman.
마법의 파괴때문에
있어야 하는데
그러나 지체할 수는 없다
먼저 진행할 것이다
But we cannot delay.
We will proceed without him.
오, 위대한 신이여...
O God of the high Gods...
당신이 세상을 창조할 때의
마법의 공이여
behold the talisman with which
you created the world and all things.
O God of Gods...
오, 위대한 신이여...
이 공은 너무 힘이 강해졌습니다...
it has become too powerful for us...
and we must destroy it
before it destroys the world.
그래서 이 공이 세상을 파괴하기 전에
우리가 이 공을 파괴하려 합니다
용서하여 주소서
마법의 힘을 빼어..
Forgive us now
as we send it out of the light...
from which it draws its power...
암흑속으로 던지니..
우리를 용서하여 주소서
into eternal darkness.
Forgive us.
Come on.
들어오라
So this can make worlds...
그래, 이것이 세상을 천둥과 지진으로...
창조할 수 있고 파괴할 수 있다니
or shatter them by storm and earthquake.
Have it lifted out.
끄집어 내라
끄집어 내라!
Lift it out!
만져라
Touch it.
정말이군, 여자만 만질 수 있어
So it is true. Only women may touch it.
뚜껑
The cover.
가지고 가
Take it out.
여왕이시여
포로들은 어떻게 할까요?
Great queen,
what shall we do with the prisoners?
-안돼!
- No!
Come.
말을
Horses.
The talisman's stolen.
마법의 공을 빼앗겼어요
Must destroy the talisman.
반드시 파괴해야 합니다
We must find my sister. Take me.
내 동생을 찾아야 해요, 데려다 주세요
어디 있는지 알아요, 제발
I know where she is. Please.
Magnificent.
훌륭해
You have nothing more to learn, Sonja.
더 이상 배울게 없어, 소냐
You are the master of the master.
너는 전사중에 전사야
당할 자가 없어
Never have l seen your equal.
조금 더 남자를 좋아하는 법을 배워야겠어
You must learn to like men a little better.
They are not all evil.
그들은 모두 악마가 아냐
경험으로 판단해야 합니다
대사님
We must judge by our own experience,
Grand Master.
I know.
알어
그러나 인생은 전부 싸움은 아냐
But in life, all is not swordplay.
Hatred of men in a lovely young woman...
사랑스럽고 어린 여자의 남자에 대한 증오..
너의 멸망이 될 수 있어
it could be your downfall.
모든 남자를 미워하는 것은 아닙니다
I don't hate all men, Grand Master.
오랫동안 들어온 말이군
That would have been music to my ears
30 years ago.
Come.
따라와라
훌륭한 전사는 훌륭한 칼을
가져야 한다
A great swordsman
must have a great sword.
Choose.
골라라
A gift from the Grand Master.
선물이다
소냐
Sonja.
왜 그러지, 소냐?
What is it, Red Sonja?
소냐를 찾는다
I'm looking for Red Sonja.
-내가 소냐다
-네 언니가 죽어가고 있다
- I am Sonja.
- Your sister's dying.
데려다 주리다
I'll take you to her.
바나
Varna.
신이여 감사합니다
Thank God.
나는 오래 못살어
I've lived long enough.
마법의 공을 빼앗겼어
The talisman's stolen.
모든 사제는 학살당하고
All the priests massacred.
- We fought...
- Rest, Varna. Later we can talk.
-싸워서.....
-좀 쉬어, 나중에 이야기하고
There's no time. Listen.
그럴 시간 없어
마법의 공은 엄청난 힘을 갖고 있어...
The talisman has terrible power...
밝은 곳에서 힘을 내지
which grows in the light.
13일 정도면 세상을 파괴할 수 있어..
In 13 days it could destroy the world...
by storm and earthquake.
천둥과 지진으로
네가 그 공을 파괴시켜, 소냐
You must destroy the talisman, Sonja.
어둠속에 집어넣어, 맹세해라
Send it into darkness. Swear that you will.
그래
I swear.
누가 갖고 있지?
Who took it?
누군지 모르겠어
I don't know.
황금가면을 쓴 여자였어
There was a woman with a gold mask.
군대였어
Soldiers.
어디로 갔어? 남쪽? 북쪽?
Where did they take it? North? South?
죽었어
그리고 산 사람은 할 일이 있어
She's dead.
And the living have work to do.
당신하곤 관계없는 일이야
Her work, my work, is no concern of yours.
-그런데, 누구지?
-칼리도
- Who are you, anyway?
- My name is Kalidor.
언니하고 친구였어, 기억나?
I befriended your sister, remember?
나는 네 친구이기도 해
I'm a friend of yours, too.
언니에게 해 준 것에 대해 고마워
보상해 줄께
I thank you for what you did for my sister.
You will be rewarded.
돈 바라고 한 게 아냐, 안받어
I'm no mercenary. Nobody pays me.
빚졌다고 생각 될때는
받겠지만
If l think somebody owes me something,
l take it.
누군가 마법의 공을 사용하고 있군
Someone is using the talisman.
-저기가 어딜까?
-하브록, 큰 도시지
- What place is that?
- Hablok. It's a great city.
어딜 가지?
Where are you going?
하브록
Hablok.
잠깐, 같이가지
Wait. I'll come with you.
당신이 왜? 당신 일 아냐
Why should you? It's no business of yours.
내 일이야
And neither am I.
둘 다 틀렸어
You may be wrong on both counts.
용감한 건 알지만
모험은 내 것이야
I know you're a brave girl,
but danger is my trade.
그럼 혼자 배워 볼께
Then l'll learn it by myself.
화나게 하지마, 칼리도
Don't make me angry, Kalidor.
난 남자의 어떠한 도움도 싫어
I don't need any man's help.
흔들리게 하지마, 바보야, 꽉 잡어!
잘해볼 수 없어?
Don't shake it, fool. Hold it steady!
Can you do nothing right?
정말 바보천치야
Still, you great idiot.
노력하고 있어요, 나리
I'm trying, Your Highness.
쓸모 없는 사람, 바보, 멍청이
쓰레기, 돼지새끼!
Clumsy oaf. Stupid, dumb,
useless, selfish beast!
빨리 와요
Quickly, come. Come to me.
명령하지 마, 노예놈아
패 버리겠어
Don't give me orders, slave.
I'll have you hung by the heels.
어째든, 너무 미끄러워
Anyway, it's too slippery.
진흙탕에 넘어지면 좋겠어? 멍텅구리야
Do you want me to fall
in that boiling mud? You numskull.
내가 돌려줄께
I'll try to swing it around. Now.
-잘 잡어, 꼬마야
-꼬마라고?
- Hold still, boy.
- Boy?
조심, 조심
Steady, Your Majesty. Steady.
뛰어 내려
Jump off. Jump.
나는요?
What about me?
여기로 다시 와
Get back here and stop playing the fool.
명령대로 갑니다
나리
I hear and obey, master of the world.
I'm coming.
이 사람 때문에 다행인 줄 알어
Lucky for you that this person came along.
상을 내려라, 그리고 내가 누군지 말해라
Reward her, and tell her who l am.
위대한 하브록의
탄 왕자님이십니다..
His Royal Highness, the Prince Tarn,
Great Lord of Hablok...
훌륭한 왕관의 군주..
keeper of the spotless throne...
세계를 다스리는
위대한 코끼리...
great elephant who fertilizes the world
with his...
그런 것은 말하지 말랬잖아
l've told you not to say that.
또 그러면, 처벌하겠다
Do it again, and l'll have you impaled.
그럼, 상을 내려라, 바보야
Well, reward her, fool.
둘러보니, 왕자님
나보다 돈이 더 필요로 하겠어
From the look of your kingdom, Prince,
you need this more than l do.
거절하네?
Did she address me?
무슨 일이지?
What happened?
게드린 여왕이 공격했어요
Queen Gedren attacked us
is what happened.
게드린? 게드린 여왕이?
Gedren? Queen Gedren?
그렇소
That's right.
신무기로 도시의 반을 날려버리고
항복을 요구했소
She knocked down half the city with her
new weapon and demanded our surrender.
군사들은 달아났지
My army ran away.
영원할 줄 아나보지?
Do they want to live forever?
항복을 거절했지
I refused to surrender.
그랬더니 나머지도 박살냈어요
So she knocked down the other half.
폴킨, 모두 죽거나 도망갔으니...
Falkon, since everyone is dead
or run away...
내일 산으로 인도해야하네
you shall escort me
to the mountains tomorrow.
새로운 군대를 만들거야...
I shall raise a new army...
그래서 이렇게 만든 게드린을 쳐부셔 버릴거야
and crush this upstart Gedren underfoot.
어디가면 찾지, 이 게드린을?
Where can l find her, this Queen Gedren?
버크밴에요, 영원한 밤의 나라요
In Burkubane, the land of eternal night.
어떻게 가지?
How do l get there?
먼 길이죠, 브라이태그의 길을 통한
지름길이 있어요
There's a long scenic way, and there's
the short way through Brytag's toll road.
브라이태그의 길로 가야겠군
어느 길이지?
I'll take Brytag's toll road.
Which way is that?
북쪽으로 쭉 가요
그럼 돼요
Straight north from here.
You can't miss it.
도움 될겁니다
But it's worth a try.
그녀가 우리의 군대에 합류하길 원하는지
물어보아라
Ask the woman
if she wishes to join my army.
취사병이 필요할건대
We'll probably need a cook.
친철도 하시지
그러나 혼자 갈거야
Your Highness is too kind,
but l travel alone.
저 여자는 보내버리고
밥이나 먹자
Dismiss the woman, Falkon.
I shall dine in an hour.
충고 한마디 해도 될까?
May l give you a word of advice?
그를 무릅에다 놓고
때려가며 버릇좀 고쳐
Put him over your knee
and beat some manners into him.
혹시 식탁보 갖고 있어요?
You wouldn't happen to have a tablecloth,
would you?
브라이태그, 나와서 문 열어라
Brytag, come down and open the gate.
Not so fast, redhead.
서두르지마, 빨간머리
네가 잘 보이는 여기에 있어
I'm up here
where l can get a better look at you.
시간이 없어
I have no time to waste, Brytag.
난 많어, 올라 와라
I have plenty. Come up, l say.
-여기로, 기집애야
-왜?
- Come here, wench.
- Why should I?
Because l am Brytag. This is my land.
내가 브라이태그야, 내 땅이니
All that pass through pay me tribute.
통과하려면 공물을 내야지
- How much, Brytag?
- Who mentioned money?
-얼마지?
-누가 돈 달래?
공물이랬잖아
Tribute, l said.
여자들은 부드러움을 내 놔
The tender kind all women pay to Brytag.
싫다면
Suppose l don't.
Suppose, instead, l open up
that great fat belly of yours.
대신에 네 뚱뚱배를 열겠디면
들었어?
You hear that?
내 커다란 배를 연다고....
She's going to open up my great...
이 여자야, 난 177명하고 싸웠어
Woman, l have fought 177 men.
한 명 살았어, 그런데 다리가 없어
Only one survives, and he has got no legs.
You dare to mock at Brytag?
감히 덤벼?
무서울 것도 없어
That takes no daring.
그런데 내가 널 죽이면
네 군사들이 날 곱게 보내주겠지?
But when l've killed you,
will your warriors let me go unharmed?
날 죽이면?
When you've killed me?
저 년이 날 죽이면
너희들은 곱게 보내줘라, 알았지?
When this wench has killed me,
you will let her go unharmed, won't you?
네
Aye.
알았어?
See?
그럼, 이 년아
So, wench.
네 눈깔을 새먹이로 주지
빨간머리야
I'm gonna feed your eyes
to the birds, red hair.
네놈은 볼 필요도 없어
I don't need eyes to find you.
100보거리에서도 냄새가 나
I can smell you at a hundred paces.
네 내장하고나 미래이야기나 할께
빨간 년아
I will tell the future in your entrails,
red woman.
난 미래가 있지만, 넌 없어
I know my future. You have none.
쳐부셔, 소냐.
Hold on, Sonja.
소냐, 이리
Sonja, come on.
조심해!
Look out!
여기로, 따라 와라!
This way. Follow me!
-가라, 가!
-당신은?
- Get away. Go!
- What about you?
저들을 막을수 있어, 가!
I can hold them. Go!
서둘러! 잡아라!
Hurry! Stop them!
놔줘, 도둑놈들아!
Release me, ruffian!
놔줘!
Release me, l say!
-어디 있는지 말해
-꿈 깨!
- Tell us where it is.
- I'll have your head for this!
속이지 마
Don't be shy.
그 금, 어디있어?
The gold, boy. Where's the gold?
금 없어
There is no gold, ruffian.
금이 없단 말이야!
I tell you, l have no gold!
좋은 옷을 입었는데
번쩍번쩍 하는 걸로
You have fine raiment, boy,
almost as resplendent as mine.
돈이 없다는 걸 어떻게 믿겠어?
And you expect me to believe
you're penniless?
말해주지, 이놈아
나는 하브록의 탄 왕자다
I'll have you know, villain,
l am Prince Tarn of Hablok.
내 신하가 꼭 널 혼내줄거야
My subjects will see
to your punishment for this.
고통스럽게
버릇없는 놈아!
And a grievous punishment it will be,
impertinent oaf!
신하?
Your subjects?
내 왕국이 네 놈 것보다 훨씬 커
My kingdom is greater than yours.
그리고 신하가 4명이야
And l have but four.
당겨!
Pull him!
-괜찮은가요, 전능하신 군주님?
-그래, 멍텅구리야
- Are you all right, your sovereign Majesty?
- Yes, clumsy oaf.
왜 그를 떠났어?
Why did you leave him?
음식이 필요해서요, 사냥갔지요
We needed food. I went hunting.
데리고 갔어야지
You could have taken him with you.
그녀에게 말하라, 폴킨
사냥에 관심없다고
Tell her, Falkon,
that l don't care for hunting.
사냥에 관심 없답니다
He doesn't care for hunting.
보물은 보물창고로
포로는 지하감옥으로
Treasure to the vaults,
prisoners to the dungeons.
마법의 공은 빛의 방으로
Take the talisman back
to the Chamber of Lights.
알겠습니다, 여왕이시여
Very well, my queen.
아마 촛불 몇개면...
Perhaps fewer candles...
충분할겁니다
would be advisable, Your Majesty.
왜?
Why?
빛이 강하면 강할수록
마법의 공의 위력이 강하니깐요
The stronger the light, the greater
the power of the talisman grows.
빛이 더 필요하다
I want more light here, not less.
그러나 벌써 위험한 힘입니다
But it is dangerously powerful already,
great queen.
-하브록에서 한 것 봤지
-네, 만족합니다
- Look what it did to Hablok.
- Yes. Very satisfying.
그러나 토크틸과 싸울 때는
강력한 힘이 필요해, 아이콜
But l want its full power
when we march against Toktyl, Ikol.
최고의 힘
Its full power.
-조절이 가능하니깐요, 폐하
-여왕폐하!
- It will be beyond our control, Majesty.
- Majesty!
적들이 국경근처에 다다랐습니다
Enemies are approaching
the outer empire.
하브록의 왕자입니다...
It's the Prince of Hablok, Your Majesty...
군사하고요
with his army.
버러지들
Insects.
그 년이다
That girl.
그래 도망친 년이지, 이런
So she escaped the fire. How fortunate.
아이콜, 저년 피부 하나 다치지 않은 채
사로 잡고 싶다
Ikol, l want her alive
without so much as a scratch on her skin.
매복조를 보낼까요?
Shall l send out a small ambush party?
아니
No.
좀 더 가까이 올때까지 기다리지
We'll wait till they get a little closer.
버크밴, 영원한 밤의 나라
Burkubane, the land of perpetual night.
폴킨, 도착을 공포하라...
Falkon, proclaim my arrival...
그리고 게드린에게 선전포고하라
and the defiance of Queen Gedren.
나팔을 불고
Sound your trumpet.
조용...
Keep quiet...
적어도 건너는 길을 찾을 때까진
at least till we find a way across.
왕자는 도둑놈처럼 몰래 쳐들어 가지 않는다
Princes do not sneak in
on their enemies like thieves.
왕자라는 것을 잘 모르는군?
You don't know
much about princes, do you?
여기 기다려
You wait here with the horses.
먼저 다리를 검사해 보겠어
I want to test this bridge first.
다른 것도
Or whatever it is.
충분히 안전하겠어
말을 끌고 가지
It looks safe enough.
We'll lead the horses across.
내 말 들어라, 게드린!
Now hear me, Gedren!
나다, 하브록의 탄 왕자..
It is I, Prince Tarn of Hablok...
버크밴의 반역자를
처단하러 왔다
to revenge myself
on the tyrant of Burkubane.
조용해, 건방지고 답답한 친구야
Be quiet, you arrogant, ungrateful pup.
감히, 여자가?
How dare you, woman?
본때를 보여주겠어
I'll show you how l dare.
일찌감치 손 봤어야 하는데
This should have been done long ago.
안돼요, 때릴려면 날 때려요
No. If you must hit someone, then hit me.
노력할 필요도 없어, 꼬마는
You're not worth the effort, boy.
꼬마?
Boy?
그래, 꼬마야, 너는 폴킨처럼 태도나
Yes, boy. You'll never be anything else...
자기희생을 배우기 전까지는...
아무것도 될 수가 없어
till you learn gratitude
and self-sacrifice, like Falkon.
진짜 남자야
He's a real man.
그녀 말 신경쓰지 마세요, 왕자님
왕자님의 진짜 능력을 몰라요
She didn't mean it, my prince.
She doesn't know your fine qualities.
덤벼, 도둑놈아
Take that, ruffian.
덤벼라
Take that, you ruffian.
연습해, 왕자님?
Practicing, Highness?
왕자들은 모든 걸 잘하는 걸로 아는데..
I thought princes did everything so well,
they wouldn't need to.
저번에 그 도둑놈들하고는
내가 무기를 놓쳐서..
I was disarmed by those ruffians
the other day.
알어, 그래서? 중요한 건 아닌데
I noticed. So? It needn't be fatal.
나 무기없어, 날 죽여 봐, 덤벼
I am disarmed. Kill me. Come on.
덤벼 봐!
Come on!
칼솜씨를 말하는거지?
You're meant to be
using your sword. Remember?
간단하네, 그렇지 않아?
Simple, isn't it?
이런 건 책에도 없어
But it's not in the rule book.
방어하는 것과 공격은 다르지
You see, fencing and fighting
are two different things.
두개를 다 배워야 해
You need to learn them both.
가르쳐 줄래?
Will you teach me to fence and to fight?
제발?
If you please?
왕자답게 말해
Spoken like a prince.
너무 칼자루를 꽉 잡아서
칼을 놓치는 거야
You were disarmed
because you hold the hilt too tight.
가볍게 잡고, 알았어?
Grip gently. See?
가볍게, 이렇게?
Gently. I see. Like this?
빨리 배우네
Your Highness learns fast.
계속 배우면 되겠어
I think we'll continue
your fencing lessons another time.
빨리 시작하지
We've an early start.
당신은 참 아름다워
You are very beautiful.
내가 하브록의 왕이 되면
궁전에 초대하지
When l am king of Hablok,
l shall have you at my court.
정말? 영광이군
You will? My, the honor.
내 왕비가 될지도
I may even make you my queen.
그러나 내가 아직 어려서
But l'm still young.
만나게 될거야
We shall have to see.
저들이 내일 이타안 동굴에 오겠군
They will reach
the Ithian Cavern tomorrow.
그 속으로 들어가게 해야 해
We must force them to take shelter there.
나머지는 죽이고
The killing machine will do the rest.
네, 물고기 밥이 되겠죠
Yes. They'll make fine fish food.
저 여자는 아냐
But not the girl.
나에게로 데려 와
I want that beauty here with me.
See to it that she is spared.
최선을 다하겠습니다
I'll do my best, my queen.
기계를 조정하기 힘들어서요
The machine is difficult to control.
잘못될지 아무도 장담 못합니다
One cannot guarantee
that something will not go wrong.
그렇게 된다면, 다음은 네 차례야
If it does, you will be its next victim.
마법의 공을, 천둥을
The talisman, Ikol. We need a storm.
약간만
A little one.
이 천둥을 벗어나야 하는데
We should be out in the storm.
왜요? 여기 동굴인대요?
Why? This is shelter, isn't it?
대피하고 있을 시간이 없어
4일이나 지났어
I haven't got time to shelter.
I've four days left to find the talisman.
그런데, 뭔가가 우릴 여기로 몬 것 같애...
Besides, something drove us in here...
수상해
every bit of the way.
내가 투덜거린 것 아닙니다
I noticed it, but l'm not complaining.
탄은 어딨지?
Where's Tarn?
옆길로 새지 않기로 했는데
옷이나 말려요, 내가 찾아 볼테니깐요
He promised not to wander.
Dry off, l'll go find him.
이것 봐
Look at this.
세상에서 제일 클거야
It must be the biggest in the world.
가짜일겁니다
그런 게 많아요
Could be fake.
There's a lot of bad stuff around.
이 진주가 하브록을 재건할거야...
This pearl can rebuild Hablok...
이 보물로 군대를 사자
fill its treasury, buy me an army.
끄집어 내라!
Dig it out!
폐하
누구의 것인지 몰라요
Your Highness,
it may belong to somebody.
그러니 빨리 파내라!
It does, and he wants it now!
네
Yeah.
칼로 해라, 바보야!
Use your dagger, fool!
뭐하는거지?
What are you doing?
물 좀 봐!
Falkon, Highness, look at the water!
힘 좀 줘 봐
Come on. Put your back into it.
꼼짝도 안하네요
안 꺼내질려나 봐요
It won't budge.
Maybe it wasn't meant to come out.
물이 차오고 있어
여기를 나가야 해
The water is rising.
You must get out of here.
-이쪽으로, 계단으로!
-가세요, 왕자님!
- This way! Make for the stairs!
- Come, my prince!
-물밖으로!
-네
- Get out of the water!
- Yes.
올라가세요
Climb up here, my prince.
탄!
Tarn!
내가 갈게요!
I'm coming, my prince!
Let go!
어딨지?
Where is she?
안죽네, 기계야!
I can't kill it! It's a machine!
소냐, 눈멀게 해야겠어!
Sonja, we have to blind it!
그 수 밖에 없어!
It's our only chance!
폴킨, 나가, 볼수 없게 됐어!
Falkon, get out! It can't see!
잘 잡어
There. Keep it covered.
왜 따라 오는거지?
Why have you been following me?
무사히 마법의 공까지 가나 보려고
To see that you reach the talisman safely.
왜?
Why?
마법의 공이 파괴되는 걸
봐야 하거든
I have to be sure
that the talisman is destroyed.
오래전에, 아르카디아 왕께서...
Centuries ago, the high lords of Arcadia...
여제사들에게 마법의 공을 주었지...
had entrusted the talisman
to the priestesses...
여자들만 만질 수 있으니
because only women may touch it.
그러나 공의 보존이나
파괴는...
But to guard it,
or to destroy it if need be...
아직 조물주의 권한이야
is still the duty of the High Lord.
당신? 조물주?
You? The High Lord?
나는 공을 파괴하는 걸 보기 위해서
온 것 뿐이야..
I was coming to the temple
to see the talisman destroyed...
내가 네 언니를 만났을 때...
when l found your sister dying...
공이 빼앗긴 걸 알았지
and learnt that the talisman
had been stolen.
그래서 언니가 너를 인도 하랬어
So she guided me to you.
당신이 누군지 왜 이야기 하지 않았어?
Why didn't you tell me who you were?
남지의 도움을 싫어하는 것 같아서
You didn't seem to want a man's help.
그러나 필요한 것 같아서
따라 왔지
But you needed it,
so that's why l followed you.
도와주고 싶어
I had to be sure you reached the talisman.
알았어
I see.
오해했어
다른 이유인줄 알았지
I misunderstood.
I thought you had another reason.
그래
I did.
안돼, 난 맹세했어
No. I'm under a vow.
싸움에서 날 이기지 못하는 남자는
날 가질수 없어
No man may have me
unless he has beaten me in a fair fight.
그러면 널 가질 수 있는 사람은
너를 정복하려하는 사람이겠군
So the only man that can have you
is one who has tried to kill you.
논리적이군
That's logic.
정복자에게만 항복한다면
정복당할 준비가 되어 있겠지
If you yield only to a conqueror,
then prepare to be conquered.
바보같은 짓 말어, 널 죽이고 싶지 않아
Don't be a fool. I don't want to kill you.
해 봐
Try it.
자
Come on.
저쪽으로 가서 해요
잠좀 자게요
Keep it down over there.
We're trying to sleep.
괜찮아?
Are you all right?
그래, 연습중이야
Yes, Prince. We were just practicing.
그럼, 내려 놔!
Then let me down!
고마워
Thank you.
왜 저 여자가 둔하게 싸우지?
Why does she fight so hard?
이기고 싶지 않나 봐
She doesn't want to win.
게드린의 군대야
다른 종족은 노예가 됐어
Gedren's army.
Another kingdom enslaved.
공을! 찾아야만 해
The talisman! We must find a way in.
올라가야 해
We'll have to climb.
세명만 올라가야 해
Three of us should go in.
누가 이 문을 지킬래?
Who'll stand guard this doorway,
the post of danger?
-폴킨?
-내가요? 여기서요?
- Falkon?
- Me? Here?
저 문에서 뭐가 나올지도 모르는대요
난 가겠어요
I don't know what's coming out that door.
No, l am going up.
겁장이!
Coward!
나는 저기서 할 일이 있는대
I'll take my chances in there.
그리고 나도 가야하고
And l have to go in.
내가 지키지
I'll stay.
조심하고, 폐하
Take care, Your Highness.
고마워
Thank you.
내일부터 살을 빼야겠어요
Tomorrow, l start my diet.
폐하, 공이 이젠 조정이 안 돼 갑니다
Majesty, the talisman
is almost beyond control.
늦기전에 어둠속에 묻어야 합니다!
We must bury it in the dark
before it is too late!
더이상 쓸모 없을 때 묻을거야
아직 시간 있어
It'll be buried when l have no further use
for it, and that time is not yet.
우릴 다 죽일겁니다!
무엇을 원하시나이까?
But it will kill us all!
O God, Majesty, what do you want?
보물창고는 금으로 가득찼어요
모든 나라가 우리에게 겁먹고 있구요!
Our vaults are brimming with gold.
Great states live in terror of us!
-또 뭐가 있나요?
-온 세상을!
- What more is there?
- The world, Ikol!
이젠 토크틸의 도시 일부를 점령했어
Today we took another piece
of the city of Toktyl.
그러나 난 더 많이 요구했고
마법의 공이 무찌를거야!
But l have wider claims
and the talisman will enforce them!
미쳤어, 그렇게 안될거야
Madness. There will be no world.
그렇게 안될거야
There will be no world.
공을 찾아야 해
나만 만질 수 있어, 명심해
We must find the talisman.
Only l can touch it, remember.
여기로 가, 난 다른 길로 가지
폴킨, 가운데로
You take that way, l'll go the other way.
Falkon, you take the center.
맛이 어떤가?
How's the food around here?
누구야?
Who are you?
-공을 찾어
-네
- Look for the talisman.
- Yeah. Right.
-아이콜, 게드린의 검은거미
-당신
- Ikol, Gedren's black spider.
- You.
그래, 하브록의 탄 왕자이다
Yes. Prince Tarn of Hablok:
너의 추악한 마술로 말했지
The city you blasted
with your filthy sorcery.
그 녀석은 이런 건 못 배웠을텐데
So the royal brat hasn't learnt his lesson.
비켜라, 꼬마야
Out of my way, child.
그런데 도망가다니?
So that you can desert,
like the thief you are?
내 금 갖고?
With my gold?
하브록의 금?
Hablok's gold?
무례하게도...
Now that was unmannerly
of Your Highness...
버릇없는 애는 혼나야 해..
and rude little boys need correction...
제대로 클려면....
if they're going to grow up into...
영원히 안 자랄 수도 있어
l'm afraid Your Highness' growth
is going to be stunted permanently.
이젠, 항복하지, 검은거미
Now, yield, Black Spider.
게드린 여왕은 어딨지?
Where's Queen Gedren?
사라져 버렸어, 만나서 반가워
She's gone. I'm so glad that you've come.
제발, 나를 보호해 줄래?
너무 무서워
Please, will you protect me?
I'm so frightened.
게드린! 어디있냐?
Gedren! Where are you?
하브록의 왕자가 어리석은 덕분에..
So the Prince of Hablok
honors us with his presence unwisely.
몇명이 왔지?
말해! 몇명이야?
How many are with you?
Tell me! How many are with you?
-몇명?
-충분히 왔다, 게드린!
- How many?
- Enough, Gedren!
돌아가라, 그러면 하브록은
왕위를 돌려 받을 것이다
Get back, or Hablok will need
an heir to the throne.
그리고 네 왕위도, 게드린
And your own throne, Gedren.
마법의 공이 어둠속으로 들어가지 않으면
네 왕국도 곧....
Unless the talisman goes into the dark,
your whole kingdom will...
왕자, 칼리도와 폴킨을 데려 와
Prince, get Kalidor and Falkon.
이 뒤에 길이 있어
There's a way behind the throne.
마법의 공을, 게드린, 빨리!
The talisman, Gedren. Quickly!
바보같으니
우린 같이 세계를 지배할 수 있을텐데
You are a fool.
We could have ruled the world together.
이젠, 혼자 할거야
그리고 네가 나한테 한 댓가로 넌 죽을거야
Now l shall rule alone,
and you will die for what you did to me.
내가 뭘?
What l did?
넌 우리 부모를 살륙했어
You slaughtered my parents like cattle.
내 형제, 동생을!
My brother, my sister!
버러지놈! 그깟목숨이 이것과 비교되겠어?
Vermin! What were their lives
compared to this?
넌 미쳤어!
마법의 공이 널 파괴할거야
You are mad!
The talisman will destroy you.
여기 위에, 소냐
Up here, Sonja.
올라와
Up here.
칼리도, 폴킨, 여기야, 빨리!
Kalidor, Falkon, this way! Hurry!
내려가!
Down this hallway!
소냐, 이쪽으로
Sonja. Over here.
도와줘
Falkon, help.
탄 왕자님, 돌아와요
Prince Tarn, come back.
내가 여기있다, 게드린, 역도들을 죽이려 왔다
I am here, Gedren. Death to all tyrants.
소냐, 도와줘!
Sonja, help me!
갇혔어!
I'm trapped!
소냐 ! 뒤를 봐!
Sonja! Behind you!
난 안되겠어
I can't get through.
그녀를 당겨, 내가 문을 들을께
Falkon, pull her through. I'll hold the gate.
따라 와, 여기가 나가는 길이야
Follow me. This is the way out.
어떻게 알지요?
How do you know, Highness?
내가 들어 왔으니 알지
밥통아
Because this is the way
l came in, you clown.
여기 길 있어
Here's the way through.
갑시다, 빨리!
Go. Quickly!
문이 안 움직이네
The door doesn't move.
어떻게 열지?
How does it open?
내가 알어, 기다려
I know. Leave it to me.
안돼요, 돌아와요!
No! Come back, Prince!
해냈어
He's done it.
그를 놔두고 갈 수 없어요
기다려요, 꼼짝말고요
We can't leave him.
Wait here, my prince. Don't go away.
도망가!
Save yourselves! Run for it!
폴킨도, 멍청이야!
You, too, Falkon, you great, clumsy oaf!
도망가! 도망을!
Run! Run for it!
혼자 갈 수 없어요
왕자님
I'm not leaving here without you,
my prince.
손을 줘요, 빼내줄게요
Give me your hand. Reach. I'll get you out.
하브록은 저기야
Hablok is over there.
다시 건설되면
만나러 와야 해
When it's rebuilt,
you must come to visit us.
언젠가 왕비가 필요할거야
I'm sure to need a queen someday.
그렇겠지
You'll find one.
누구든, 신중히 골라
Whoever she is, Prince, choose carefully.
나와 싸워서 이기지 못하면
안 된다는 규칙을 만들어
I make it a rule never to take a woman
unless she can beat me in a fair fight.
언젠가 도전해볼만한 거군
That's a challenge
l might think about someday.
지금 어때?
What about right now?
왜 못하겠어?
Why not?
가자고, 폴킨
Come along, Falkon.
가자
Come on.
English